

MSc · IMAGE PROCESSING SCIENTIST · RESEARCHER

□ (647) 224-8873 | saqeeb@saqeeb.com | saqeeb.com | saqeebhassan

Summary _

I'm an image processing scientist that recently received an MSc in Medical Biophysics. I worked on novel imaging pipelines and image quality evaulation metrics for faster MRI scar mapping in patients with ventricular tachycardia. I am most proficient in Python.

Skills_

Programming Proficient: Python. Comfortable: Pytorch, Pandas, Pillow, Matlab, Git. Some Experience: Java, Javascript, LaTeX

Research Project-based work, Scientific and Technical Writing, Data Analysis, Operating an MRI Scanner **Science** Image Processing, Signal Processing, Machine Learning, Medical Imaging, Physics, MRI Physics

Education

M.Sc. in Medical Biophysics

Toronto, Canada

University of Toronto

January 2018 - September 2021

Reduced scan times for MRI scar mapping in ventricular tachycardia patients by over 70% by implementing novel, underutilized imaging
pipelines and reconstruction techniques

B.Sc. in Physics, with Distinction

Kingston, Canada

QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY

September 2013 - June 2017

• Undergraduate thesis: Investigated rotational dynamics of disk galaxies by simulating them as a series of concentric massive rings which interact with one another gravitationally. This was to model the disk warping of galaxies such as UGC 3697

Work Experience _____

Sunnybrook Research Insitute

Toronto, Canada

RESEARCH SCIENTIST

September 2021 - Present

- Developed two novel MRI sequences using the Javascript-based MRI platform 'RTHawk' by HeartVista to enable faster data acquisition in timesensitive scans
- Developed image quality evaluation metrics for comparing novel imaging pipelines against the clinical standard to validate results. These included measurements for image sharpness and signal-to-noise comparisons
- Engaged with patients while operating the MRI scanner to ensure a good experience for them

Queen's University Kingston, Canada

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May 2016 - September 2016

- · Organized and preprocessed data for a research lab investigating chronic kidney disease in rat models
- · Evaluated the lab's data analysis needs and carried out the transition to Microsoft Access for database functionality
- Interacted with animals to perform daily data collection

Awards

2018-2019 Queen Elizabeth II Graduate Scholarship in Science and Technology, U of T and Province of Ontatio 2019-2020 Queen Elizabeth II Graduate Scholarship in Science and Technology, U of T and Province of Ontatio

Extracurricular Activity _____

Social Committee President

Toronto, Canada

GRADUATE STUDENT ASSOCIATION

January 2018 - January 2020

- Improved the graduate student experience by organizing social and networking events for students in the Department of Medical Biophysics
- Determined the best use of the events budget and developed strong interpersonal skills

Let's Talk Physics Symposium Co-organizer

Kingston, Canada

LET'S TALK SCIENCE December 2016

- · Led a team of physics students in organizing a successful science outreach effort hosting over 200 local high school students
- Was featured in a local newspaper article here